The battle for Earth has begun
The Second Arrival is a science fiction, horror film directed by Kevin Tenney.
After Zane Ziminski is found dead five people received
envelopes with details of an alien invasion.
This group of five includes 3 scientists, Zane's brother Jack, and a reporter.
Quickly, the group is down to three and then Jack and Bridget, the reporter.
With a small piece of alien technology, they must escape from the aliens, who
take human form, and try to convince others that aliens exist.
Jack Addison, played by Patrick Muldoon.
Bridget Riordan, played by Jane Sibbett.
Prof. Nelson Zarcoff, played by Michael Sarrazin.
Sandra Wolf, played by Catherine Blythe.
Wolan, played by Michael Scherer.
Burke, played by Larry Day.
Arrival is a 2016 American science fiction drama film directed by Denis Villeneuve and written
by Eric Heisserer, based on the 1998 novella "Story of Your Life" by Ted Chiang.
The film stars Amy Adams as Louise Banks, a linguist enlisted by the United States Army to discover how to
communicate with extraterrestrials who have arrived on Earth, before tensions lead to war.
Jeremy Renner, Forest Whitaker, and Michael
Stuhlbarg appear in supporting roles.
Arrival had its world premiere at the Venice Film Festival on September 1, 2016, and was
released theatrically in the United States by Paramount Pictures on November 11, 2016.
It grossed $203 million worldwide and was widely praised, particularly for Adams's performance,
Villeneuve's direction, and the exploration of communication with extraterrestrial intelligence.
Considered one of the best films of 2016, Arrival appeared on numerous critics' year-end lists and
was selected by the American Film Institute as one of ten "Movies of the Year".
It received eight nominations at the 89th Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best
Director, Best Cinematography, Best Adapted Screenplay, and won Best Sound Editing.
For her performance, Adams received nominations for a BAFTA, SAG, Critics' Choice; at the 74th Golden Globe Awards, Adams was nominated for
the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress and Jóhann Jóhannsson was nominated for the Golden Globe Award for Best Original Score.
The film was awarded the Ray Bradbury Award for Outstanding Dramatic
Presentation and the Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation in 2017.
The score by Jóhann was nominated for Best Score Soundtrack
for Visual Media at the 60th Grammy Awards.
The film explores themes of extraterrestrial technology,
investigation, global warming, space invasion, sequel.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.